Let's look more closely at how sequence to sequence models
我们再仔细研究下序列到序列模型的
work.
工作原理
We'll start with a high level look
我们先从更高层面去了解
and then go deeper and deeper.
然后逐渐深入讲解
Here are our two recurrent nets.
这是两个循环神经网络
The one on the left is called the encoder.
左侧的叫做编码器
It reads the input sequence, then
负责读取输入序列
hands over what it has understood to the RNN
然后将所发现的规律传递给
and on the right, which we call the decoder.
右侧的 RNN 我们称之为解码器
And the decoder generates the output sequence.
解码器会生成输出序列
The quote unquote "understanding"
传递给解码器的“规律”
that gets handed over is a fixed size tenser
是固定大小的张量
that is called a state, or sometimes called the context.
称为状态 有时候叫做上下文
C is for context here.
C 表示上下文
So no matter how short or long the inputs and outputs are,
无论这里的输入和输出有多短或多长
the context remains the same size
上下文的大小保持不变
that was declared when we built the model in the beginning.
我们一开始构建该模型时就声明了它的大小
So at this high level, the inference process
从高的层面看就是
is done by handing inputs to the encoder.
推导流程是将输入传递给编码器
The encoder summarizes what it then
编码器将所发现的规律
understood into a context variable or state.
总结为上下文变量或者叫状态
And it hands it over to the decoder,
并传递给解码器
which then proceeds to generate the output sequence.
解码器然后加以处理并输出序列
Now if we go a level deeper, we begin
如果我们再深入看看
to see that since the encoder and decoder are both RNNs,
我们发现 因为编码器和解码器是 RNN
they have loops, naturally, and that's
它们自然都有循环
what allows them to process these sequences of inputs
这样才能处理这些输入和输出
and outputs.
序列
Let's take an example.
我们来看个示例
Say our model is a jackpot, and we
假设模型是个聊天机器人
want to ask it, "How are you," question mark.
我们想问“How are you ?”
So first, we have to tokenize that input,
首先我们需要把句子拆成单词
and break it down into four tokens.
将其分解为四个小块
And since it has four elements, it
因为有四个元素
will take the RNN four timesteps to read
所以该 RNN 需要四个时间步长
in this entire sequence.
来读取整个序列
Each time, it would read an input,
每次都会读取一个输入
and then do a transformation on its hidden state,
然后在隐藏状态上进行转换
then send that hidden state out to the next time step.
并将该隐藏状态发送给下个时间步长
The clock symbol indicates that we're moving from one timestep
时钟符号表示我们将时间步长
to the next.
往后移了一个
One useful way to represent the flow of data through an RNN
表示 RNN 数据流的一种实用方法是
is by "unrolling," quote unquote, the RNN.
“展开”RNN
That is, graphing it to show each timestep
即用图表将每个时间步长
as a separate cell.
表示为一个单独的单元
Even though, in practice, it's just the same cell.
虽然实际上是同一单元
Only it's processing a new input,
只是处理了新的输入
and it's taking over the hidden state
并包含上一个时间步长的
from the previous timestep.
隐藏状态
So, what's a hidden state, you may ask.
你可能会问 什么是隐藏状态
In the simplest scenario, you can think of it
最简单的情况下 可以想象为
as a number of hidden units inside the cell.
单元中一系列隐藏的单位
In practice, it's more likely to be
实际上 更有可能是
the hidden state inside a long, short-term memory
长短记忆网络 (LSTM) 单元中的
cell, an LSTM.
隐藏状态
So, the size of the network is usually another hyperparameter
网络大小通常是我们在构建模型时
that we can set to build the model.
可以设置的另一个超参数
The bigger the hidden states, and the bigger the
隐藏状态越大
size, the more capacity of the model
网络大小就越大 模型的学习容量越大
to learn, and look at patterns, and try to understand them.
并越能查看和了解规律
But the more resource intensive the model
但是训练或部署所需的资源也越多
will be to train or deploy, in terms of processing and memory
也就是对处理器和内存
demand.
要求越高
So it's that trade-off that you usually
所以通常你需要
face with models, in general.
对模型的这一利弊进行权衡
A similar process happens on the decoder side, as well.
解码器也是类似的流程
So we begin by feeding it this data generated by the encoder.
我们向其提供编码器生成的数据
And it generates the output elements by elements.
然后逐个元素地生成输出
If we unroll the decoder, just like
如果像之前展开编码器那样
we did earlier with the encoder, so we
展开解码器的话
can see that we are actually feeding it back every element
我们可以看到我们实际上不断把输出当作新的
that it outputs.
输入 传入到模型中
This allows it to be more coherent as each timestep
这样更具连贯性
sort of remembers what the previous timestep has committed
因为每个时间步长都能差不多记住上一个时间步长的
to.
内容
In the next video, we'll go another level deeper
在下个视频中 我们将进一步了解
into some of the internals of the architecture.
该结构的一些细节部分